(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-18T09:55:38.270802",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
こんばんは。
Good evening.
周年おめでとうの時間です。
It's time to celebrate our anniversary.
さて本日は白上の「おめでたい」日を祝しまして、ゲーマーズの皆さまと
Today, to celebrate Shirakami's special day with all the Gamers...
地方旅してきた様子をお届けします。
we'll share footage of our trip to the countryside.
何やら前半に詰め込み、スケジュールがタイトなようなんですけども
Apparently, we crammed a lot into the first half, so the schedule seems pretty tight, but...
果たして日頃の疲れを癒すことはできるのでしょうか？
I wonder if we'll be able to wash away our daily fatigue?
それではゲーマーズ旅スタートです！
Now then, the Gamers trip begins!
おはようございます〜！
Good morning~!
もうすぐね、みんな来てるかな？来るかな？
Almost everyone, are they here yet? Are they coming?
と思うんですけども
I think, but...
どっかいるかな？おるかな？
I wonder where they are? Are they here?
あ、なんか見えるぞ！なんかトボトボ歩いてきているふたりが見える！
Oh, I see something! I see two people trudging over!
おはようございます！
Good morning!
おはようございま〜す… おはようございま〜す…
Good morning... Good morning...
現在朝の06:30頃ですか？おはようございます皆さん！
It's currently around 6:30 in the morning, right? Good morning everyone!
元気すぎん？なんか。
You're way too energetic, somehow.
眠いのかい！？
Are you sleepy!?
なんで呼び出されたのこんな時間に！
Why were we called out at this hour?!
今日なんて聞いてました？
What did you hear today was about?
え？え、なーんにも聞いてないよ！
Huh? Eh, we didn't hear anything at all!
とりあえず、なんか「明日まで予定空けといてください」
All we heard was, "Keep your schedule open until tomorrow."
明日まで予定空けといて下さい
Keep your schedule open until tomorrow.
今日はね、ちょっとあの「ゲーマーズ」でね、行きたい所があるんですけども
Today, we Gamers have somewhere we'd like to go, but...
え？ え？ゲーマーズ？
Eh? Eh, Gamers?
そう、ゲーマーズで
Yeah, at Gamers—
ひとり足りなくない？
Isn't someone missing?
見当たらない…ひとり見当たらないですが？
Nowhere to be seen... One person is missing, you know?
あの、まぁ、まぁ、ちょっとね。あの、もうひとりはちょっと置いときまして
Ah, well, you know... we'll leave another person behind for now—
置いとくの！？
Leave them behind?!
ちょっと置いときまして、早速ちょっとバス用意してますので
Leaving them behind, we've prepared a bus for us, so
バス？
A bus?
乗っていきましょう
Let's ride it!
レッツゴー！！
Let's go!!
え、ガチの貸し切りバスじゃん！
Whoa, it's a real chartered bus!
ガチのバスでございます
It is indeed a real bus.
遠足じゃん！遠足だ！
It's a field trip! A field trip!
早速ね、中に乗っていきましょう
Let's get inside right away.
え、こん…すごい！
Whoa, con... amazing!
どう行くんだ、こんなんで
How are we supposed to ride like this?
ころね〜！おるやんけ！
Korone~! She's right here!
嘘でしょ？
No way, right?
どうしたの？
What happened?
みんな〜！おはよ〜おはよ〜！
Everyone~! Morning, morning!
すんごい小っちゃくなっちゃってるけど…こんな姿になっちゃった
She's become super tiny though... She ended up looking like this.
このころねを今日は連れていきま〜す
We'll be taking this Korone with us today~
え〜！？え〜！？
Eh~?! Eh~?!
よろしくね！
Treat me well!
ちょっと苦しそうまであるけどね
She even looks kind of constrained, though.
ごめんねころね
Sorry, Korone.
というわけで、バスの中 でございますけども
So, we're inside the bus now, but...
今日はこんな朝早くから集まってどこに行くと思いますか？
Where do you think we're going, gathering this early in the morning?
みんなほんとにさ、わかんないからさ
We really have no idea, you see.
フブキちゃんの実家
Fubuki-chan's parents' home.
行かないわ！なんでやねん！
No way! What's with that?!
遠いな、おい
That's far, man.
違う、違う、違うの！
No, no, that's not it!
え、違うの？
Eh, it's not?
今日はですね、ま、ね、日頃いろいろいっぱいね、遊んでもらってみんなもお仕事大変な中なのでゆっくりしてもらおうということで
Today, since you all play with us so much every day and work so hard, we wanted to let you relax, so—
今回は……草津に行きます！
This time... we're going to Kusatsu!
うわーーー！
Whoaaa!
草津うう！？
Kusatsu?!
草津といえば？
Speaking of Kusatsu?
温泉！？
Hot springs?!
すごくない？台本ないのにめっちゃ被ってるよ！ハモリまくってるわ！ハモリ具合半端なかったわ今
Isn't it amazing? Even without a script, we're completely in sync! We're harmonizing like crazy! The harmony was unreal just now.
今回なぜ草津に行きたいかと言いますと、まぁ我々さ、このまぁ、この長い付き合いの中で温泉行ったりさ、そのグランピングとか行ったりしたんだけどさ
If you ask why we want to go to Kusatsu this time, well, over our long time together, we've gone to hot springs and glamping and all that, but...
その時に、なんか今後行きたい温泉どこが良い？みたいな話をね、実にしたことがありまして
Back then, we actually had a conversation about where we'd want to go for hot springs in the future.
したっけ？そんなこと
Did we? Something like that?
したよ！！したんだよ！！白上は覚えてんだよ！！
We did!! We totally did!! Shirakami remembers it!!
それで、行ったことないから草津温泉行きたいな、みたいな話をね、渋川から確かしたんだよね。で、草津もいいね、みたいな話で
And so, since we've never been, I mentioned wanting to go to Kusatsu Onsen starting from Shibukawa, and we agreed Kusatsu sounded nice.
なので、今回ねこれを機に草津温泉に行こうじゃないかということで、まあじゃあ……
So, taking this opportunity, why don't we head to Kusatsu Onsen? So, well then...
フブキが行きたいからってこと？
You mean because Fubuki wants to go?
そうです
That's right.
そういうことかあ〜！
Ah, so that's how it is!
ちょっとバスに揺られながらのんびりと草津へ向かおうと思いま〜す！もちろんね、ここにいる
We'll head to Kusatsu leisurely while riding the bus! And of course, right here with us—
ころねも一緒なのでね。こんな姿になっちゃって…こんな姿になっちゃったからにはね。なんかだから、ころねの心の声をさ、おかいやん？ちょっと聞いてみるね
Korone is with us too. Since she's in this form... now that she's ended up like this, let's hear Korone's inner voice, Okayan? Let's listen in.
うれしいいい〜
I'm so happyyyy~
そんなんだったっけ？
Was it really like that?
うれしい！ころねも草津、好き〜！
Yay! Korone loves Kusatsu too~!
なんかすごい、ちょっと、ちょっと誇張されてるw
It feels a little... a little exaggerated lol
ころさんも喜んでるよ！喜んでる、喜んでる！
Koro-san is happy too! She's happy, she's happy!
ということでね、このままのんびりのんびり行こうと思いま〜す！草津だ！いくぞー！
So, we'll keep going at a leisurely pace! It's Kusatsu! Let's go!
この先に行くと湯畑があるらしいんですよ
If you go this way, there's supposed to be a Yubatake hot water field.
え？
Eh?
湯畑ってなに？湯葉？湯葉じゃない
What's Yubatake? Yuba? It's not yuba.
湯畑がたくさんあるから湯畑なんですよ
There are lots of hot water fields, hence Yubatake.
そういうこと？
Is that so?
ほう、もすごーーい！
Whoa, it's amaziiiing!
湯気が！本当だ、なんかモクモクしてる。
The steam! It's true, it's all steamy.
なんかちょっと近くに行ってみたいな
I kind of want to go a bit closer.
匂いもすごい、温泉のね、硫黄の匂いがしますし渡っていきますか
The smell is incredible too, we can smell the sulfur from the hot springs. Shall we walk across?
え、どうなってんのこれ
Eh, what is this like?
すごい
Amazing.
すごい、茹で卵の匂いする
Wow, it smells like boiled eggs.
茹で卵の匂い作ってんのかな？ここで、茹で卵そんな大量に…？
Are they making boiled eggs here? Boiling that many eggs...?
温泉、すごっ、凄まじい
Hot springs, wow, incredible.
うわ、こっちはこっちですごいね、めちゃキレイ
Whoa, this side is amazing too, super pretty.
温泉の滝だ〜！！
It's a hot spring waterfall!!
温泉の滝
A hot spring waterfall.
こっちすごいよ
This side is amazing.
ねえ！すごいザーってなってる
Right! It's gushing down like crazy.
ウォータースライダーみたいになってるよ、温泉のウォータースライダーだ！すごっ
It looks like a water slide, a hot spring water slide! Amazing!
モクモクもすご〜い
The steam is super amazing too.
すごいね、めっちゃ手洗い浴びてる、マイナスイオンする
Amazing, we're getting sprayed so much, feeling the negative ions.
うわ、モワっとする！！
Whoa, it's so humid and warm!!
うわぁぁ〜！！
Whoaaa!!
良い感じに湯畑も撮れましたので、次の目的地に行きましょう！！おっおい、じゃあレッツゴー！ゴーゴー！ゴーゴー！レッツゴー！
Well then, we got some great shots of Yubatake, so let's head to our next destination!! Hey hey, let's go! Go go! Go go! Let's go!
西の河原公園には何があるんですか？
What's in Sainokawara Park?
さあ何があるでしょうかね…？
Well, I wonder what's there...?
あ！足湯がある！足湯があるんですねぇ！
Oh, there's a foot bath! There's a foot bath!
すげえ！
Awesome!
なんか地面から煙出てない？ 出てるー！
Hey, is smoke coming out of the ground? It is!
もしや温泉…？ 掘ったら出る？
Could it be a hot spring...? If we dig, will it come out?
温泉じゃない？ あ、ほんとだ、温泉だね！
Isn't this a hot spring? Oh, true, it's a hot spring!
ここも温泉なのー!? すごい、これ温泉だ！
This is a hot spring too?! Wow, this is a hot spring!
緑だなぁ。綺麗だね。緑だなぁ。
It's so green. It's beautiful. So green.
温かいですか？
Is it warm?
温かーい！！全然触れる！
Waaarm!! I can totally touch it!
温かさ。あったかい位なんだ。
It's about that warm, huh.
あ、なんか、看板立ってるよ？
Oh, look, there's a sign up?
鬼の相撲場ってありますよ。
It says "Demon's Sumo Ring".
え！？相撲しようぜってこと？
Eh?! Does that mean "Let's sumo"?
パン、相撲しようぜ！パン！みんなでこの後…
Pan, let's sumo! Pan! Everyone, after this...
稲荷神社って書いてある。ほんとなんだ。
It says Inari Shrine. Oh, really.
本日はここですね。目的は？ここなの？ここのお稲荷神社でーす！
Today's destination is here. Is it here? It's the Inari Shrine here!
よいしょ、登って、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ！
Heave-ho, climbing up, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho!
お稲荷さんもマスクしてる！ほんとだー！
Even the fox statues are wearing masks! That's true!
こちらのですね、砂をおうちに持って帰って家で撒くと、ご利益があると言われております。
It is said that if you take this sand home and sprinkle it around, you'll receive blessings.
まずは、あれでしょ、お参りからですね。はい。
First of all, we should start with worship, right?
お賽銭あげる瞬間をもうわかんなくなっちゃったけど、先に上げるんだっけ？先に上げるんだ！
I forgot the exact moment to give the offering, but you give it first, right? You give it first!
で、こちらの砂ね。スプーン1杯欲張るとご利益は半減してしまいます。
And this sand. If you are greedy and take more than a spoonful, your blessings will be halved.
欲張りさんはダメだって！よかった！じゃあスプーン1杯分持って帰りましょう！
Greedy people are no good! Good! Then let's take a spoonful home!
じゃあ僕から。取りすぎるとあれだから、こんぐらいにしようかな。商売繁盛。
Then from me. Taking too much is bad, so I'll make it about this much. Prosperity in business.
かなり安全。心願成就っていうのかな？厄除け開運とか交通安全病気。
Quite safe. "Shinigan Seiju" (fulfillment of wishes)? Ward off evil, good fortune, traffic safety, illness.
はい、取りました。オッケー！いっぱい。すり切れ？すり切れ！
Okay, I took some. Okay! A full spoonful. Level? Level!
はい、お砂もね、ころねにも砂を…あ、じゃあころねの分も、ころねも200円…じゃあころねの分僕がお願いしとくから、ちょっと待ってね。
And for Korone too... Ah, then for Korone's share, Korone also paid 200 yen... Well, I'll pray for Korone's share, so wait a minute.
お金を先に入れて…はい、お願いします。
Put the money in first... Yes, please.
じゃあころねの分の砂もね、あんまり入れすぎると良くないみたいだから、ちょっとだけ、こんくらい、こんくらい。
And for Korone's sand too, putting too much seems bad, so just a little bit, this much, this much.
ころねのやつ？あ！ころねのやつ！ありがとー！！ころねのやつー！
Korone's? Ah! Korone's! Thank you!! Korone's!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
温泉に向けてね…そうそう足早に、足早に行きましょう…！わぁー！
Heading toward the hot springs... Yes, let's walk fast, let's walk fast...!
フブキちゃーん…！やめろー！寄りかかり攻撃！
Fubuki-chan...! Stop it! Leaning attack!
フブキちゃんに引っ張ってもらおう…やめてくれえー！！
Let Fubuki-chan drag us along... Stop it!!
こっち、こっち。坂です。うわあー！うわあー！激坂だあー！！
This way, this way. It's a slope. Whoa! Whoa! It's a steep slope!!
温泉の為に頑張ろう…！そうだ！大股で歩くぞ…！温泉のためだ！
Let's do our best for the hot springs...! That's right! Let's take big steps...! For the hot springs!
お袖で…よっし、よっし、よっし！汗かいてきっけえー！
With sleeves... Yo-shh, yo-shh! We're sweating!
はい、気合入れていきます。はい！はい！激坂だあ…坂続く。
Okay, let's keep going with spirit. Yes! Yes! It's a steep slope... The slope continues.
たんぽぽお。たんぽぽ、やばい、たんぽぽ、現実逃避し始めてる。
Dandelions. Dandelions, oh no, dandelions, starting to escape reality.
頑張ろうみんな！頑張ろう！よいしょ！
Let's do our best everyone! Let's do our best! Heave-ho!
でも景色はすごい！まあ確かに。
But the scenery is amazing! Well, true.
だいぶ登ってます。景色はいいわなあ。頑張ろう！頑張れ！あとちょっとだ！
We've climbed quite a bit. The scenery is nice. Let's do our best! Hang in there! Just a little more!
しばふだらだあ…
It's a lawn...
おおーー…！！着いたー！！
Whoa...!! We've arrived!!
頑張って登ってきたねー！
We worked hard to climb up here!
激坂を登りましたけども大丈夫ですか2人とも。息も絶え絶えですよね…
We climbed the steep slope, but are you two okay? You're out of breath...
もう、とりあえず…とりあえず、ね、冷たい飲み物飲みたい！温泉に入りに行きましょう！
Already, for now... for now, you know, I want to drink something cold! Let's go take a hot spring!
さあ、こちらでございます。お、なんか綺麗な感じだ。
Now, here it is. Oh, it feels kind of nice and clean.
めちゃめちゃ綺麗な感じでございます。こちらをじゃあくぐって。はい！行きましょう！
It's extremely clean. Let's pass through here. Yes! Let's go!
行ってみますか。
Shall we go check it out?
はーい。
Yeah.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
では扉を抜けまーす。はい。
Now, let's head through the door. Okay.
おおー！
Whoa!
すごい。
Amazing.
すごい！
Awesome!
よいしょ、こんにちは〜！
Hello there~
予約してた白上です！はーい。
I'm Shirakami, with a reservation! Yes.
本日デイユースプランでお待ちしておりました。
We've been expecting you for the day-use plan today.
はい。お風呂のご案内いたしますのでどうぞ。
Yes. I'll guide you to the bath, please right this way.
はーい、行きましょうじゃあ。
Okay, let's go then.
おとなの湯失礼しまーす。
Excuse us into the ladies' bath.
おおー！すごい綺麗！
Whoa! So clean!
じゃあここで靴を脱ぐ感じですかね？
So we take off our shoes here, right?
はい。
Yes.
あったか。
It's warm.
ね、あったかいね。
Yeah, it's warm.
中もうあったかいよ。
It's already warm inside.
行きましょう。
Let's go in.
じゃあここで、劇坂のぼって疲れたのをちょっと癒しますか。
So let's unwind a bit after climbing that steep slope.
いぇーい！
Yay!
はい、じゃ行きまーす。温泉、レッツゴー！
Okay, here we go. Hot spring, let's go!
おおー！すごい、お風呂！露天風呂だー！
Whoa! Amazing, a bath! An open-air bath!
すっごーい！
So awesome!
景色すごい綺麗！
The scenery is so pretty!
すごいね。反対側もあるんですけど、まずはこっちの露天風呂、露天風呂！
It's amazing. There's another side too, but first, this open-air bath!
おおー！露天風呂！すごーい！
Whoa! An open-air bath! Awesome!
溢れてるよもう！
It's already overflowing!
めちゃめちゃ溢れている！
It's overflowing so much!
寒っ！！わあー！
So cold!! Whoa!
めちゃ、めちゃめちゃ溢れてる！
So, so much is overflowing!
お湯だ、お湯だ。
Hot water, hot water.
邪魔邪魔だ。で、みおさんとおかゆさんが遊びに来たら外返してあげる。
And if Mio and Okayu come to visit, we'll let them outside.
なるほどね。わかりました。
I see. Understood.
入って、入って、入って！
Get in, get in, get in!
どうぞどうぞ入ってください！
Please, go ahead and get in!
どうぞ。
Go on.
やばい！あっちい！結構熱い！
Oh no! Hot! Quite hot!
本当！？結構熱い！熱い！
Really?! Pretty hot! Hot!
あっつい！あっつい！あっつい！
Hot! Hot! Hot!
熱っ！！！
Hot!!!
熱！熱い！熱い！これやばいぞ。
Hot! Hot! Hot! This is crazy.
ぐおおおおおお…！うわあ！熱い！尻尾ビリビリくるうーー！
Guoooo...! Whoa! Hot! My tail is tinglinggg!!
尻尾が、尻尾がビリビリする！これはビリビリする。
My tail is tingling! This really tingles.
すごい！
Amazing!
ジワジワするよね？
It gives a tingly warmth, right?
そうそうそう！すごいジワジワする。
Yeah, yeah, yeah! It's so warmly tingly.
これ効能なの？
Is this because of the minerals?
なんだろうね？あ、高温だからなのかな？
I wonder why? Ah, is it because it's high temp?
すごいなんかバチバチするよね。
It has a sort of buzzing feel to it.
そうそうそう！すごいお肌に染みると言うか。
Yeah, yeah, yeah! It really sinks into the skin.
染みるよね！これが気持ちいい…濃い温泉って感じがするー！
It sinks in! This feels so good... feels like a rich hot spring!
そうそうそうそう！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
はあ〜！気持ちよっ！
Ahh~! Feels so good!
あ、なんかぴゅってしてる！
Ah, someone's shooting water!
あ、ぴゅっぴゅしてる！
Ah, shooting water!
手で水鉄砲を作って水を飛ばすミオ。
Mio makes a water gun with her hands and shoots water.
え、すげえ上手！
Whoa, super good!
やったことないんだけど。本当だ。
I've never done that. True.
すごくなーい？
Isn't it amazing?
うまっ！
So good!
水飛沫！片手で出来るのすっご！！
Water splash! Doing it with one hand is amazing!!
プロじゃーん！
You're a pro!
プロだったらできる、プロだったら。
If you're a pro you can, if you're a pro.
ぴゅーん！すっげえ！
Pew~! Awesome!
ええ！？どんなの？
Huh?! What kind?
え、これ見てみて！
Hey, look at this!
みおしゅもきつ…すごい！
Mioshu too—so cool!
なんでそんな飛ばせるの？すごい！
Why can you shoot it that far? Amazing!
ぴよーん。
Pew.
なんだそれ。
What is that?
両手だともっと勢いすごいけどね。
It's even more powerful with both hands, though.
うわっ！
Whoa!
びちゃびちゃ！すっごい！
So drenched! Awesome!
ほいっ！お、上手！
There! Oh, good job!
両手なの？片手なの？
Both hands? One hand?
これはね、あの、あれですよ、センスありですよ。
This is, well, you know, showing some real talent.
マジで？
Really?
僕のも見て！
Look at mine too!
うん。
Yeah.
頑張れ、頑張れ、がんばれがんばれ！がんばれ、頑張れ！
Do your best, do your best, go go! Do your best!
どう？センスあり？
How is it? Got talent?
「並」って感じです。
It's pretty "average."
なみ…？なみです。
Average...? It's average.
一句出来たのでよろしいでしょうか？
I've come up with a haiku, if you'll allow me?
お、できた！巫女川柳？
Oh, you made one! Miko haiku?
じゃあ、いきますよ。
Alright, here it goes.
草津の湯、ビリビリ来るのが癖になる、大神ミオ。
Kusatsu's hot springs, the tingling sensation becomes addictive, by Ookami Mio.
癖になっちゃったか。
It became addictive, huh.
「草津」と「癖」がなんかちょっとね、こういうこと！？
"Kusatsu" and "addictive" kind of... wait, is that what you mean?!
さすがだなあ〜。そうそうです。はい。
That's our Mio. Exactly. Yes.
俳句の格好してるだけあるな。
You really act like a haiku poet.
さすがっすね。やっぱね。かっぽ…おっ。
As expected. Indeed. Kappo... Oh.
日々の疲れ、なんだか今日でなくなりそう、猫又おかゆ。
Daily fatigue, somehow feeling like it'll vanish today, by Nekomata Okayu.
確かに、なくなりそう。
True, it really feels like it'll vanish.
ふぶちゃんは？
How about Fubu-chan?
ゲーマーズ、ゲームもいいけど、湯も良いね、白上フブキ。
Gamers, gaming is great, but hot springs are nice too, by Shirakami Fubuki.
足つりそうになった…！！
I almost got a cramp in my leg...!
なんでええ？？
Whyyy??
なんで？
Why?
そろそろ上がりますか？次がありますのでね。
Shall we head out soon? We have our next stop, after all.
はい、行きましょうかでは。
Yes, let's go then.
名残惜しいけども、良いお湯でした！
We hate to leave, but it was a great bath!
あちあちだったね。
It was nice and piping hot.
あちあちだね。
Piping hot.
ゆったり休憩タイム
[Visual: Relaxing break time]
っていうことで、温泉も上がりまして、ゆっくりしておりますけれども。
And so, we've finished up at the hot spring and are relaxing now.
どうでしたか？温泉。
How was it? The hot spring.
いや、アッツアツだったねえ。
Man, it was piping hot.
あっつかったねえ。
So hot.
気持ちよかったあ〜。
It felt so good~
すごい気持ちよかった。
Felt amazing.
満足ですねえ。
Very satisfying.
もう帰るだけかな？
Just heading back now, huh?
もう帰るだけ。もう帰るだけだね。
Just heading back. Just heading back now.
え、まだコーナーとも合流してないんですよ！？
Wait, we haven't even joined up with Corner yet!?
まだころねも合流してないんですよ！
Korone hasn't joined us yet!
そういえばそうだった
Oh yeah, that's right.
忘れ去られてた
She was totally forgotten!
なんかね、ころね、ころねのぬいぐるみがいたから、今泳いで走って来てくれてるんだから！
Her Korone plushie is with us, so she's swimming and running all the way here right now!
このあとは宿泊所に行くんですけども、なんとここね、湯上がりにアイスが頂けたということで
We're heading to our lodging next, but apparently you can get ice cream after a bath here!
さっきね、みんなでアイスをちょっと食べたんですけど、ちょっと我慢できずにペロリといただいちゃって
We all had some ice cream earlier, couldn't help devouring it right away...
チョコレートの飲み物もあったしね、美味しかったよ～！
They also had chocolate drinks, and it was so delicious!
美味しかったね。紅茶も頂いちゃいましたね、紅茶も！
It was delicious. We had some black tea too, black tea!
めちゃめちゃ美味しい湯上がり癒やし薬なんですが、このあとは宿泊するところに移動したいと思います
It's the ultimate post-bath remedy. But after this, we'll be moving to our lodging!
果たして…テントなのか…！？野宿 or テントかってこと？野宿とテントの二択ヤバくない！？
Will it be... a tent...?! Wild camping or a tent?! A choice between wild camping and a tent is brutal!
え、嘘でしょ！？野宿とテントの二択ヤバくない！？何なのか！一体どこに泊まらされるのか！
No way, seriously?! Where on earth are they making us stay?!
でもすご～くいいところです！マジ！？えぇ！？
But it's a suuuper nice place! Really?! Eh?!
なのでこのままね、またあの坂を…っ！えっ嘘でしょ…！？汗だくだくになっちゃうよ～！と思ったんですけど
So we'd have to walk down that slope again...?! No way...?! We'd be drenched in sweat! That's what we thought, but
バスが来るそうです！
apparently a bus is coming!
お迎えに来てくれますのでね、今回はね、あのゆったりしたのでバスで行きましょう！
They're coming to pick us up, so since it's relaxing this time, let's take the bus!
ね、湯上がりに尽きりだ！やったー！
Yay! Complete post-bath bliss! Yay!
はい、ということで、着きました！
Alright, so we've arrived!
本日泊まるとこはここでございます！ここですか？はい！こちらですね、きむらや別邸といいましてプライベートコテージと！
The place we're staying today is right here! Here? Yes! This is called Kimuraya Bettei, a private cottage!
え？プライベートコテージ？そうなんです！そのような物があるんですね！
Eh? A private cottage? That's right! They have places like that?!
はい、こちらに今日は一泊します！すげえ！
Yes, we'll be staying here for one night! Awesome!
レッツラゴー！レッツラゴー！
Let's go! Let's go!
お！おーすごい！もう玄関広い！おー！すっごい！廊下すごくない！？
Oh! Whoa, amazing! The entryway is huge! Whoa! Incredible! Isn't this hallway amazing?!
リビングだぁ～！！
It's a living room!!
すっご～い！
So awesome!
広い！すっごい広い！広いです！めちゃ広いじゃん！
It's wide! It's so wide! It's super wide!
照明もおしゃれ！ねえ、おしゃれな空間となっております！すごーい！
The lighting is stylish too! Look, it's such a stylish space! Amazing!
こちら、あ、お風呂？なんと、お風呂！
Over here, oh, a bath? An actual bath!
見てください、お風呂！うわあ、すごい！うわあ！
Look at this, bath! Wow, amazing! Whoa!
なんとこちら源泉でございます！ほんとだ！うわあ！源泉かけ流しでございます！
This is a natural hot spring source! Really! Wow! It's 100% natural hot spring water!
すんげえんだけどこれ～！他のところもどんどん見に行っていいよ！いちょー！
This is insane! Feel free to go check out the other rooms too! Let's go!
今日はこちらでね、一泊しようと思います！楽しみ！楽しみ！
So we'll be staying here for one night! I'm so excited! So excited!
みなさん、キッチンがあるということは…え？？
Everyone, the fact that there's a kitchen means... Eh??
今日の晩御飯は…え？みんなでご飯を作りまーす！ええ～！？
Tonight's dinner is... Eh? We're going to make dinner together! Eeeeeh?!
主にみおちゃんしか料理できないんじゃないの～！？いやいやいやいやそんなことないだろ！
Isn't it mostly Mio-chan who can actually cook?! No, no, no, no way!
内容にもよるでしょ！今日はみんなでカレーを作っちゃおうかなと！すごーい！カレー！？
It depends on what we're making! Today we thought we'd make curry together! Amazing! Curry?!
みおちゃんがんばって！！おいおい！！お前も頑張るんだよ！！
Mio-chan, do your best!! Hey, hey!! You're going to work hard too!!
普通のカレーじゃあれなのでね、ゲマズらしいカレーを…ゲマズらしいカレー？アレンジは危険だぞ！！
Since regular curry is boring, we wanted to make some Gamer-esque curry... Experimenting is dangerous!!
誰にも内緒でみんな1人ずつ入れたいものを買って入れてみよう！ということで、闇カレーってこと？そう、闇カレーですね！
Keeping it a secret from everyone, we each bought one ingredient we wanted to add and tried tossing it in! So, dark curry? Yes, dark curry!
フブキちゃんのことだから辛いの入れんじゃ無いの上？食べられないものはまずいのでね、美味しくなりそうなものをね、やろうと思いますので
Knowing Fubuki-chan, you probably put something spicy in! Inedible things are gross, so we'll pick things that'll actually taste good.
はあ、ここでちょっとゆっくりしてましたけども、いやあ、そうだねえ…
Ah, we were relaxing here for a bit, but man, yeah...
どうした！？そうだねえ…どうした！？軽く寝てたか！？軽くというか…結構がっつり寝ちゃったねえ…
What happened?! Yeah... What happened?! Did you take a quick nap?! Well, not quite quick... I fell asleep pretty deeply...
このあともご飯も食べたんだけど、あ、スマホが！鳴ってる！電話！もしもし～？？
We ate dinner after this too, oh, my phone! It's ringing! A phone call! Hello~??
もし～？
Hello~?
ころね！！ころねさん！！もしもし！
Korone!! Korone-san!! Hello!
楽しんでる～？
Are you having fun~?
「楽しんでる？」じゃないよ～！楽しんでるじゃねえんだよ！
Don't ask \"are you having fun~\"! We're not just having fun!
今どこにいるの！？さっき仕事終わって、んで今、迷いながらもうすぐ着きそう！
Where are you right now?! I just finished work, and now I'm getting lost but I'm almost there!
やっぱ走って来たかもしれない！歩いて来た歩いて来た！ゆっくり来た～w ゆっくり来たんだ！
Maybe she actually ran here! She walked! She walked! She came slowly lol She came slowly!
ごめん、あのさぁ…爪が伸びたのね？え、どういうこと？なんの話？
Sorry, um... your nails grew, you see? Eh, what do you mean? What are you talking about?
爪が伸びたから、爪切りあったら置いといて欲しい！wwwwwwwww
My nails grew, so if you have nail clippers, I want you to leave them out for me! wwwwwwwww
爪切りあったかなー？爪切りあんのかなー？わかんないけど…爪切りあったらよろしく！ちょっと聞いとくね！
Wonder if we have nail clippers? Wonder if there are any? If there are, please! I'll ask around!
じゃあ待ってるよ～！待っててね～！はーい！はーい！
Okay, we'll be waiting~! Wait for us~! Okaaay! Okaaay!
だってさ、あ、お、なんか来たよ！来いよ！入ってきて！あ、お！
She said that, oh, oh, someone's here! Come on in! Come on in! Oh, oh!
ころね？もしかして
Korone, is that you?
到着したのか？
Did you finally arrive?
爪大丈夫だった？？
Are your nails okay?
いや、今の感じじゃ見えなかったけどね、爪は。
Well, from how it looks now, I couldn't really tell about your nails though.
ほんとに？
Really?
キタ〜〜！！やっと来たじゃ〜ん！
She's here! She finally came!
爪見して？
Let me see your nails.
ほら！言うほど伸びてないｗ
Come on, they're not that long!
そんなじゃ、ｗ
What on earth?
何してたの？
What were you even doing?
寝てたよ、寝てたの。
I was sleeping!
荷物さ、みんなのさ、
Wait, aren't all our luggage...
あれ、上に置いちゃってんの？
Oh, they're left upstairs, aren't they?
上置いた。そうそうそうそう。
Yeah, I put them up there.
上行こ〜！ｗ上に置いちゃった
Let's go upstairs!
この後何するの？
So what are we doing after this?
この後はですね、みんなでご飯を買いに行くよ。
After this, we're all going to go buy food!
ご飯買いに行くの？
We're going to buy food?
そう、今日みんなでご飯作るんだよ。
Yeah, today we're all making dinner together!
あ、じゃあ、あれ？「何にもなってないやつ」を買うの？
Ah, so we're buying "plain" stuff?
そうそうそう「何にもなってないやつ」ｗ
Right, right, right! "Nothing yet"!
材料をね、そう、買ってここで作るんだよ！
Yeah, so we buy the ingredients and make it here!
聞いてねぇ！！
You're not listening at all!
行こう行こう！行こう！行こう！行こう！や、行こう！
Let's go!
いもんの、いもんの、いもんのか！よいしょ、よいしょ。
There we go, there we go!
買ってきた。
We bought them!
じゃあ、とりあえず基本の材料を買ってきた。じゃあ、こちらのほうに置きましょうか。フブちゃん。
So, first let's introduce the basic ingredients we bought.
はい、はい、はい、はい。基本の材料、まず、こくまろ甘口。
Okay, okay! The basic ingredients first...
そして、ジャワカレーの辛口。
And then, Java Curry in mild.
にんじん！にんじん！にんじん！
Carrots!
たまねぎ！たまねぎ！たまねぎ！
And onions!
そして、そして、はい、じゃがいも！じゃがいも！
And potatoes!
あ、これが基本ですね。
So that's the basics.
確かに、基本セットだね。
Right, exactly.
はい、じゃあここから追加したものをじゃあ白上からいきましょうか。
Now, let's announce what extra ingredients we added, starting with Fubuki's.
よくいっぱい入ってんな！
Oh, wow, you have a lot in there!
まずは！
First is...
鶏肉！鶏肉だ！すごい！いいぞ！鶏肉だ！
Chicken!
そしてパプリカ！パプリカだ！パプリカだ！
And paprika!
ナス！ナスいいよ、ナス！いいね、ナス！おいしいよね！
Eggplant! Oh, nice!
たまご！たまご！
Eggs!
ほたて！ほたてね！ほたて！ほたてを入れるってこと？
Scallops! You're adding scallops?
そう。
Yup.
鶏肉！かぶった！かぶった！
Chicken! Wait, mushrooms!
シーフードミックス！だ！シーフードだ！
Seafood mix!
みんながそんなお肉買ってくると思わなくて…
I didn't think everyone would buy meat...
天然えび（デカイやつ）！まあ美味しくはなるんじゃない？
Jumbo shrimp! Well, it'll still taste good, right?
シーフード鶏カレーってこと？
So it's seafood chicken curry?
お肉を切りま〜す！
I'm going to cut the meat!
お肉切ります！お肉切ります！
Oh, cutting the meat!
はいはい、切ってくれ。はい。
Okay, cut it up nicely.
これちょっと皮剥かなきゃいけないね。
Wait, we have to peel these potatoes too, right?
やばい、難易度高いよ、ころさ〜ん…！
Oh no, the difficulty is high here, Korone...!
大丈夫！
You'll be fine!
皮なんか切ったことないよ…。
I've never even cut a potato's skin before...
包丁でいける、大丈夫！
Just use a kitchen knife!
お粥を作ったのがね、
Since you made okayu before...
みんな食べたいから。
Everyone wants to eat, so...
マジで〜？
Seriously?
これを混ぜていきます。
Now, I'm going to mix this up.
混ぜ混ぜ。みおしゃ、どんな感じ？
Mix, mix! Mio, how does it look?
いや、今ちょっとカオス状態だよ。
Well, it's in a pretty chaotic state right now.
まじか。
Seriously?
お、こぼれてこないようにね。
Make sure it doesn't spill over, okay?
トマト、油とヨーグルトだわ。ただ。
Tomato, oil, and yogurt...
これ、ナンって解凍中これ？
Is the naan defrosted already?
どうやってじゃがいもの皮って剥くんだろ…
How do you peel a potato's skin anyway...
ふえぇ…？？
Eh...?
芽は取ってね？芽は。
Make sure you take the sprouts out, okay?
芽？芽ってどれぇ…？
Sprouts? Which ones are the sprouts?
芽、食べちゃうからね。
If you eat those, you'll get food poisoning!
ころさん、これ芽？
Korone-san, is this the sprout?
そうよ。それも取ったほうがいいいね。
That's it. You should remove that too.
豪快…豪快だ。
Bold... That's bold.
猫又おかゆの豪快Cooking！！
Nekomata Okayu's Bold Cooking!!
豪快なの…？
Is this bold?!
豪快じゃない…！！
It's not bold at all!!
普通、普通、それ。
That's just normal!
そんな風に思ってた？
Is that what you thought?
いやそれが普通だっ…マジで普通から…
No, that is totally normal!
豪快だって思ってた？
You thought it was bold?
へへへ、なんか顔みたいだね。
Heh heh heh, it kinda looks like a face.
おまえを食ってやろうかぁ！
I'm gonna eat you up!
パプリカマンだ！！
It's Paprika Man!!
パプリカマンだ！
Paprika Man!
増殖した！
Divided!
おまえを食ってやる！子分だ！
I'm gonna eat you up, minion!
3匹になった！アッアッアッアッ
There's three of them now! Ha ha ha!
だめだよご飯で遊んじゃ！！
Hey, stop playing with your food!
遊んでないよ…。
I'm not playing...
もちもちだねぇ。
It's so squishy!
もちもちだよ。ナンってそうやって出来るんだ。
So this is how naan is made.
すっげえ！
Amazing!
え、すごーい！すごーい！
Whoa, incredible!
じゃあうちは15分寝かせてる間、
While ours rests for 15 minutes,
ちょっとシャボン玉をしてきます。
we're going to go blow some bubbles!
やった！いいね！
Yay, sounds fun!
楽しそうかよ。
This'll be fun!
白上もしてこようかな。な。そう。
I think I'll go do some too.
いぇーい！シャボン玉しちゃお〜。
Yay! Let's do bubbles!
皆さんこれが白上フブキが吹いているシャボン玉です綺麗でしょう？
Everyone, this is the bubble-blowing Shirakami Fubuki. Pretty, right?
おーいっぱい出てます。綺麗ですねえ。
Whoa, there are so many! It's pretty!
アッ…
Ouch!
シャボン玉が目にっ…
A bubble went right in my eye!
あーシャボン玉が…弾けたっ！くらってます。
Ah, the bubble popped! It hit me!
にんじんっ。
Carrots...
一回ゴミ捨てよ。はい。
Let's throw the ends away first.
良いじゃなしかぁ？
Looking good, isn't it?
ナスはヘタだけ取ったらいいのかな？
Should we just take the stem off the eggplant?
そだよ〜！わかった。
That's right!
すごい、みおママ無干渉でございます。
Amazing, Mio-mama is completely neglecting her duties.
完全に無干渉、満喫しまくってる。
Completely neglecting them, just resting away.
はい。
Yeah.
もうちょっとね…疲れたので少し休憩しております。
Well, I'm a bit tired so I'm taking a short break.
みおしゃｗ
Mio-sha!
せいおしゃ。
とりあえず、じゃあ炒めるほうから入ったほうがいいね。
Well, we should probably start with the stir-frying part.
そうだな。たまねぎ切れてるならたまねぎから炒めたほうがいい。
That's true. Since the onions are sliced, we should stir-fry those first.
たまねぎこの底に入ってる。
Wait, the onions are right at the bottom!
あ、でもあんまりうちも口出さない方が良いね。
Well, we shouldn't open our mouths too much either.
経験者として口出そうとしちゃったけど…
Even though I tried to give advice as an experienced cook...
え、でも口出してほしい！
Eh, but we want you to speak up!
本当？うん！
Really?
そしたらぁ！
Then!
ふふふｗそしたらぁ！
Haha!
たまねぎをまず炒めて
First, stir-fry the onions...
First, stir-fry the onions.
鶏肉は別のフライパンで炒めて焦げ目付けておいた方がいいよ
And stir-fry the chicken in a separate pan, it's better to brown it.
なるほど〜？
I see~?
たまねぎある程度炒まったら
Once the onions are stir-fried to a degree,
にんじんとうパプリカも一緒に炒めちゃって
stir-fry the carrots and paprika together as well.
がんばって炒めて～
Hang in there and stir-fry them~
がんばって
Hang in there!
僕の切ったナスです
These are the eggplants I cut.
ナス～！
Eggplant~!
ナス見てころさん！ここ切り目入れたんだよ！
Look at the eggplant, Korone-san! I made cuts in it!
切り目入れたのね！偉いねぇ～！！
You made cuts in it! That's so good!!
切り目職人おかゆが！
Okayu, the incision artisan!
おかゆ料理上手いもんね！！
Okayu is good at cooking, after all!!
…ありがと
...Thank you.
お刺身シーフードを炒めたいと思います！はいお願いしまーす
I'd like to stir-fry sashimi seafood! Yes, please.
何故かカレー班に加わっている
For some reason, it's joined the curry team.
カレー班に加わった
It joined the curry team.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
うわすごい！エビ大占拠
Wow, amazing! Shrimp landslide victory.
エビすごいよ！
The shrimp is amazing!
エビでかすぎない？このエビ
Isn't this shrimp too huge? This shrimp.
エビ軍やばい！
The shrimp army is crazy!
でかいエビ、これの汁だけこの中に入れて、あとは焼きたいなちょっとやっぱ
Big shrimp, just put the juice of this inside, and I want to grill the rest a bit, after all.
わ～寝ちゃうこと、これ寝れるな、これ寝れるな
Wow, I'm gonna fall asleep here, I can sleep here, I can sleep here.
もうふぶきちゃんを枕にしたらちょうどいい
It's just right if I use Fubuki-chan as a pillow.
助けてええ！
Help meee!
ミオしゃパン屋さんみたい！
Mio-sha looks like a bakery!
お前だろパン屋さんは！
You're the bakery, aren't you!
都会にあるパン屋さんにいる犬。店番をしながら空いた時間にゲームをしている。
A dog in a bakery in the city. Tending the store and playing games in her spare time.
ちょっと一枚目を焼いて様子を見ております、えい！
I'm baking the first one to see how it goes, yay!
良い感じじゃ～ん！！ナンナン！
Looks pretty good!! Naan naan!
ナンになったミオしゃです、ミオしゃ～？
It's Mio-sha who became naan, Mio-sha~?
ナーーーン！！
Naaaan!!
ミオしゃん？うちうち！
Mio-shan? Uchi uchi!
ナンしゃ？なーん！
Nan-sha? Naaaan!
ミオしゃ？うちうち！
Mio-sha? Uchi uchi!
ナンしゃ？なーん！
Nan-sha? Naaaan!
ミオしゃ？うちうち！ナンしゃ？なーん！
Mio-sha? Uchi uchi! Nan-sha? Naaaan!
これ終わんの…？
Will this end...?
これ終わんの？もう一個ないと！ちょっと簡単すぎるよｗ
Will this end? You need another one! It's a bit too easy lol.
天神ミオ作 特製ナン（カレー用）
Specially made naan by Mio Tenjin (for curry)
着火！！
Ignition!!
アチャあああ！！
Ouchhh!!
ゆっくりゆっくり
Slowly, slowly.
跳ねないように上からじゃなくて、ギリギリくらいまで持ってって…ね、一個ずつね、うん
So it doesn't splash, not from above, bring it right to the edge... right, one by one, yeah.
先生ルー溶けました！
Teacher, the roux has melted!
溶けました？本当ですか！？
It melted? Really!?
まだまだ塊ありそうだけどな…
There still seem to be lumps though...
溶けたよ先生ルー…あっ本当だ！
It melted, teacher's roux... Ah, really!
え、早いね！消えるの早いね！
Eh, that's fast! It disappears fast!
美味しそう
Looks delicious.
早く浴びたいね
I want to bathe in it soon.
カレーを…？
Curry...?
頭から…？ｗ頭はやだね！
From the head...? lol Head is no good!
どこから？食道かな
From where? Esophagus, I guess.
あ、なるほどね？口から？大げさな食事の表現だったのね
Ah, I see? From the mouth? It was an exaggerated expression for eating.
流し込むってことね？
You mean pouring it down?
カレー完成？？
Curry complete??
完成です！
It's complete!
いえぇ～い！！やった～！
Yaaay!! Yay~!
味整いました
The taste is adjusted.
名前はどうします？何カレーです？
What should we name it? What kind of curry is it?
ゲマズのぶち込みカレー…って名前がちょっと変だけど
Gemaz's stuffed curry... though the name is a bit weird.
間違ってないけどぶち込みカレーやな。ぶち込み
It's not wrong though, it's stuffed curry. Stuffed.
じゃあ食べますか。はい。食べましょうでは
Shall we eat then? Yes. Let's eat, then.
いただきま～す！！
Itadakimasu!!
なんただなんだ
What in the world.
うわなんだなんだ！
Wow, what is this!
あ、じゃがいもいい感じ
Ah, the potatoes are just right.
本当は？
Really?
美味しい！
Delicious!
具たくさんやな。いいね
Lots of ingredients. Nice.
けっこうスパイシー
Quite spicy.
でもこれぐらいの辛さちょうどいいかも
But this level of spiciness might be just right.
ねえ！
Right!
うまー！
So good!
えびの味がすごい！
The shrimp flavor is amazing!
えび見つけた？
Found the shrimp?
イカかな？これもうさ、シーフードが分かんなくて肉かと思って食べたらいかだったっぽい
Is it squid? This, you know, I didn't know what seafood it was, thought it was meat, but when I ate it, it seemed like squid.
何が入ってるかわからないこのドキドキ感いいね
This suspense of not knowing what's inside is nice.
初めてカレー作ってみて…うーん、楽しかったね
Making curry for the first time... Um, it was fun.
なんか…次は一人で作れるかも！うん！
Somehow... Next time I might be able to make it alone! Yeah!
ミオちゃんにいっぱい研修してもらったからね
Because Mio-chan gave me a lot of training.
まあなかなかねこうやってゲーマーズで集まることもね、年に1回しかないからね
Well, it's rare for Gamers to gather like this, only once a year.
じゃあ次は来年？来年！？
So next year? Next year!?
でも次は来年だねって、おかゆのライブで言ってたよね？ってことは？
But you said "next year will be the next time" at Okayu's live, right? Which means?
多いんだよ今年は！
There's a lot this year!
多すぎるとちょっとね…！
If there's too much, you know...
いいことやん多いのは！！
Having a lot of good things is great!!
バランス調整して来年は会わないでおこう
Let's adjust the balance and not meet next year.
ウソでしょ！？
You're kidding, right!?
お腹いっぱいだぁ
I'm so full.
具だくさんだからね
Because there are so many ingredients.
ごっちょおしゃまでした
Thanks for the meal!
ごっちょおしゃま！
うますぎたな これ
This is too good.
ころね お風呂入ってこようかな？
Korone, should I go take a bath?
お風呂行くんだー
Ah, yeah, I'm going to the bath.
さっき入ってないよ、いってらっしゃい
You didn't take one earlier, have fun.
いってらっしゃーい
Have fun~
ころね お風呂行ってくらーい
Korone is going to take a bath~
うちらさっき入ったからね
We took one earlier, though.
じゃあ ちょっといただいちゃいまなーす
Well then, I'll take a little...
はーい、いってらーい、いってきまーす
Yay, have fun, I'll be back.
うわ～気持ちいい～！
Whoa, feels so good!
わ～～～！
Whoa~~~!
めちゃ気持ちいい～！
It feels amazing!
フウフウ！！
Whoo hoo!!
ころね～！
Korone~!
ころね～！！わ～！！
Korone~!! Whoa~!!
ころね～！！一緒に入ろ～！！
Korone~!! Let's get in together~!!
一緒に入ろ～！！めっちゃ気持ちいいよ、本当に
Let's get in together~!! It really feels amazing, seriously.
あははははははは！
Ahahaha!
すごい！みんなで入るとさ、溺れちゃうよ
Wow! If everyone gets in, we're gonna drown!
うわあああ！！！
Uwaaaah!!!
あったかいね、うわあ、気持ちいい！気持ちいいね
It's warm, wow, it feels good! It feels great.
お湯もいいな、このまま寝れるで
The water is nice, I could fall asleep right here.
ここで寝てもいいのかな？
Can we sleep here?
※お風呂で寝るのはやめましょう
*Do not fall asleep in the bath.*
やばいやばい、危ない、危ない
No no, danger, danger!
溺れちゃうよ
You'll drown!
ねぇ、お肌ころねもツルツルになりそうないや
Hey, Korone, my skin is gonna be super smooth too—
もうツルツルだよ、ほら
It's already smooth, look.
いや～んツルツル～！！
Nooo, so smooth~!!
ミオしゃは？あっやだ、ツルツル～！！
What about Mio-sha? Ah no, so smooth~!!
タオル準備するの忘れたから、一回ちょっと…
Ah, I forgot to get my towel ready, so just a sec...
僕も～、一回ちょっとタオル取りに行こう～！
Me too~, let's go get our towels real quick~!
これって湯足せないの？
Can't you add more hot water to this?
ブシュウっ！！
*Splash!!*
きゃああああ！！！うおおお！！
Kyaaaaaah!!! Uooooh!!
はははははww
Hahaha www
お湯出てくる…
Water's coming out...
あ、熱っ！
Ah, hot!
こっちはあれなのかな？
I wonder what this side does?
消灯どっきりにまで 3 2 1
Until the lights-out prank... 3, 2, 1
うわあっ！！ちょっと何すんの！！！やめてよぁ～！！
Whoa!! What are you doing?! Stop it~~!!
うおおおい！！！お前の時もやるぞ！！
Uooooy!!! I'll do it to you next time too!!
めっちゃ暗いんだけどマジで！マジで暗い！マジで暗いからな！！
It's seriously super dark! Seriously dark! It's seriously dark, you know!!
覚えとけよ！
Remember that!
ばか
Idiot.
就寝
Sleep
はあ、お風呂から上がりまして
Phew, we're out of the bath.
さっぱりしましたね～！
We feel so refreshed~!
このままみんなの布団が…
And now everyone's in bed together...
ない、イチャつくな！！！
Hey, stop being all cozy/flirty!!!
おかころがずっとイチャついてんだよなぁ
Okakoro have been flirting the whole time.
イチャイチャしてないよ
We're not flirting.
あとでね…
Later, then...
「あとでね」！？冗談冗談
"Later, then"?! Just kidding, just kidding.
どういうことなん
What does that mean?
眠くなったよぉ～
I got sleepy~
ねぇ、眠くなったよねぇ
Yeah, we got sleepy, right?
じゃあ電気消します？
Shall I turn off the lights then?
電気消すのからの～？？からの～？？
Turning off the lights... and then~~?? And then~~??
「からの」なんだよ！！
What's with "and then"?!
ほら寝ろほら寝ろ寝ろ寝ろ！
Come on, go to sleep, go to sleep!
消しますよ
I'm turning them off.
いいよ
Okay.
ちゃんと寝ろだよ
Make sure you sleep properly.
はーい
Okaaay.
おやすみになって
Have a good sleep.
はーい
Okaaay.
おやすみ～
Goodnight~
おい、ちゃんと寝とるか？
Hey, are you actually sleeping?
起きてる
I'm awake.
起きてるじゃねえか
You are awake!
さすがにね、眠れんよ
Naturally, I can't sleep.
眠いよ
I'm sleepy.
明日早いもんね
Tomorrow's early, after all.
そうだよ、朝も早いからね
That's right, morning comes early too.
オール！！オール！！
All-nighter!! All-nighter!!
やべえ、元気なやついるって！
Oh no, there's an energetic one here!
おかゆ！おかゆ！こら！！
Okayu! Okayu! Hey!!
おいちょっと！イチャつき警察だ！！
Hey wait! It's the flirting police!!
なんだよお
What is it?
いやあ、今日は歩いたしね
Man, we walked a lot today.
うんね
Yeah.
お風呂も入ったし
We took a bath too.
うんね
Yeah.
体温か
Our bodies are warm.
ね、ぽかぽかのね
Yeah, cozy and warm...
ぽかぽかだ
Cozy and warm.
大丈夫？おかゆ襲われてない？
You okay? Okayu, aren't you getting attacked?
なんか乗っかってるけど大丈夫
Something's on top of me, but I'm fine.
イチャコラ警察出るぞ
The flirting police are coming out!
あ、イチャコラ警察出たな
Ah, the flirting police are here.
イチャコラ警察来るよ？
The flirting police are coming?
あ、いいの？
Oh, really?
じゃあ電気つける？
Shall I turn on the lights then?
やめろおおおおお！！
Stop it!
電気消すなよ
Don't turn off the lights!
イチャコラ警察だ、ばか
Flirting police, idiot!
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
よろしい
Very well.
ちゃんと寝ます…
Then we'll sleep properly...
ちゃんと言ってください
Please say it right.
おやすみなさい
Goodnight.
今日からホロライブは…「アイドルレスラー」を目指すことになりましたーっ！！
Starting today, Hololife... has decided to aim to become "Idol Wrestlers"!!
5周年も…ムキムキツネ♡
Even for the 5th anniversary... buff fox ♡
5周年でも 自分らしく…
Even for the 5th anniversary, staying true to myself...
わしゃがなのマフィア梶田です
I'm Mafia Kajita from Washagana.
わしゃがなの Nakamura Yuichi です
I'm Nakamura Yuichi from Washagana.
わしゃがなの白上フブキです
I'm Shirakami Fubuki from Washagana.
はい、いらっしゃい！
Yes, welcome!
いらっしゃい！
Welcome!
フブキちゃん、いらっしゃい！
Fubuki-chan, welcome!
わー、本当にあの邪魔しまーす！お邪魔しまーす！
Wow, thanks for having me! Thanks for having me!
ついに来てくれたね
You finally came.
まあ、そうなんだけど出力先が違うぜ？
Well, yeah, but the output destination is different, huh?
あ、ちょっとそうですね、出力先のチャンネル登録者数が違うぞ
Ah, right, the subscriber count of the output channel is different.
いや俺も気になったんすけど、なんか聞いたらこっちのルールでやっていいって話だったんで
I was curious too, but when I asked, they said we could do it by their rules.
あ、そうです
Ah, is that so.
じゃあ我々です
Then it's us.
そうそうそう、こっちのルールでやらしてもらいますよ
That's right, we'll do it by our rules.
我々ですよ
It's us.
まずね、フブキちゃんは初期からわしゃがなTVを応援してくれてる
First of all, Fubuki-chan has been supporting Washagana TV since the beginning.
そうですね、もうあの番組が始まってっていう時からもう
That's right, ever since the show was about to start...
「わ！キタ！」と思って、ハイメンバーシップにも入らせて頂いて
Thinking, "Wow, he's here!" and even joining his membership.
聞いたところによると、フブキちゃんは元々中村悠一のファンなんですよね。
From what I heard, Fubuki-chan was originally a fan of Yuichi Nakamura.
そう、そうですね。
Y-Yeah, that's right.
大体そうなの。あのファンて人はそれ以上語ってくれないの。
That's pretty much it. Those fans won't talk about it any further.
いや、なんかもう、いつもそうなの。いつももう慣れっこですよ。
No, it's always like that. I'm already used to it.
「あ…そうなんですよ！」…(沈黙)
"Ah... Is that right!" ... (Silence)
御本人様を目の前にして、そういうあの限界を迎えて良いのかって本当に
Right in front of the person himself, is it really okay to reach my limit like that?
良いんだよ！
It's fine!
良いんですか!?
Is it really fine!?
良いんだよ！
It's fine!
中村悠一さんがおるうぅ↑
"Yuichi Nakamura is hereee↑!"
ほんとにいらっしゃるッ！
"He's actually here!"
そうなったらやっぱやりづらいからね。まあそういうことだよ。
Once it becomes like that, it's hard to work with, right? Well, that's how it is.
今日はね、我々の事をもっと知ってもらおうと思って、やっぱ私物紹介、よくやるじゃない。
Today, to let you know more about us, we're doing our usual personal item introduction segment.
やってますね、やってらっしゃいますね。
You guys do that, don't you?
これは初対面を知る上でね、非常に役立つ企画なんだけれども、今回はね、また色々持ってきたんで、私物紹介からお届けしていこうかなと思いますよ。
This is very useful for knowing people upon a first meeting, but since we brought various things this time, we thought we'd start with introducing our personal items.
じゃ、中村さんからお願いします。
Then, Nakamura-san, if you please.
はい、あの、こちらなんですけども、
Yes, um, as for this one,
ブルガリ！？
"BVLGARI!?"
どうですね、腕に。おぉ～腕時ィ、腕時計。あら、いやらしいもん、ブルガリの腕時計って。
How's that, on the wrist? Ohh, a wristwa-, a wristwatch. Oh my, how vulgar, a BVLGARI wristwatch.
これが、あの、自分が30歳になった時に、ちょっと頑張った価格の物を買おうと思った、記念にね。13年前、13年前買った時計
That's right. When I turned 30, I decided to buy something priced a bit out of my comfort zone as a commemorative item. I bought this watch 13 years ago.
1年で壊れました。
It broke in a year.
えっ！？
Eh!?
あの、なぜかと言うと、ハードユーズなんですよ。
You know why? Because of hard use.
めちゃめちゃ使ったんですかそれ？
You used it that much?
あの、後で気づいたんですけど、こういう時計たぶんハードに使わないんですよ。
Well, I realized later, you probably shouldn't use a watch like this heavily.
もう常に、どこ行くにもコイツと一緒だから、
I was constantly with this guy wherever I went,
1ヶ月後ぐらいに、あの、見たらわかるんだけど、あの、めちゃ傷だらけなんだよ。
About a month later, as you can see, it's just covered in scratches.
もう、こすれまくってるから。
Because it kept rubbing against everything.
それにその時計の形状をね、腕に沿うように丸型になってます。あ、結構やってますね。
Plus, the shape of the watch curves to fit the wrist. Ah, it's pretty beaten up.
新人の時にはマネージャーに言われたの。ペンと時計と靴は頑張って良いものをつけろって。
When I was a newcomer, my manager told me, "For pens, watches, and shoes, work hard and wear good ones."
なんか、アニメの現場だと関係ないんだけど、ナレーションの現場とか行くとやっぱりそこで、まあ、汚い話だけど、稼いでいるかどうかを見る＝仕事をしてる人かどうかを見るから
In anime recording sessions it doesn't matter, but in narration sessions, to put it bluntly, they look at whether you're earning well, which equals seeing if you're a working professional.
どう思った？フブキちゃん。
What did you think, Fubuki-chan?
いや、いいです、やっぱ時計持ってらっしゃるのすごい今想像して、あぁ～良いな…
No, it's great. Imagining him wearing a watch right now, I thought, "Ah, how nice..."
お前全肯定だな！
You agree with everything!
全肯定です！やっぱこういうのとか中村悠一さんにも
I agree with everything! After all, stuff like this for Yuichi Nakamura as well...
俺に有利に進むぞ！
This is going in my favor!
全肯定男だから。
Because he's a "yes-man".
今だともう本当に中村悠一さんのアニメとかゲームとかいろんなとこで見,見るんですけども、やっぱりその新人の頃をもう少し今想像して、あぁ良いなっていうのが…
Nowadays I see Yuichi Nakamura in anime, games, and all sorts of places, but imagining back when he was a newcomer makes me think, "Ah, how nice..."
でしょうね～！！
I bet so!!
こいつのオタク仕草は極まっ取る！
This guy's otaku behavior is off the charts!
いやいやいや、なかなか聞けないエピソードが聞けてよかったです。
No, no, I'm glad I got to hear an episode you rarely get to hear.
方向性間違えたかな？
Did I get the direction wrong?
なんかね、せっかくフブキちゃん来るから、フブキちゃんにプレゼントも兼ねて私物紹介をするっていうふうに思ってたんよ俺は。で、だから色々持ってきたんだけど、もうこれ全部君にあげる前提で持ってきたから。
You see, since Fubuki-chan was coming, I thought I'd do a personal item introduction as a sort of present for her. So I brought various things, assuming I'd give all of them to you.
ええ、全部ですか！？
Eh, all of them!?
そう。
Yeah.
ちゃんと言葉の裏を取って。
Make sure to read between the lines.
言葉の裏を取ると「逃げれないよ」って事？
Reading between the lines means "you can't escape," right?
で、まずはこっち。
Now, first is this one.
ON SLICE
よく分かりません、オンスライスは。
I don't really know what On Slice is.
じゃあなんで紹介したんだよ！
Then why did you introduce it?!
なぜなら、あの俺はサングラス集めの趣味だって言ったじゃないですか。これもサングラスなんですけど、だと、だと思った。うん。ただ、あの、インスタグラムって見ます？インスタ見てるとたまに広告入りませんか？そのねサングラス売ってたんですよ。で、インスタグラムで買い物したことねぇなって思って、そっから飛んで買ってみたんですよ。
Because, as I said, I have a hobby of collecting sunglasses. This is also sunglasses, or so I thought. Yeah. But, you know, do you use Instagram? Sometimes ads pop up while scrolling Instagram, right? They were selling sunglasses there. And thinking I'd never bought anything on Instagram, I clicked through and bought it.
そしたらね、赤いし、バネついてんのよ。その赤いのはヘルシングでしか見たことないです。
And when it arrived, it's red, and it has springs. The only time I've seen red like that is in Hellsing.
ちなみに今俺がかけてんのがヘルシングモデルなんだけれども。まあこれもね、あのデザインが面白れえなと思って買ったんだけれども
By the way, the one I'm wearing right now is the Hellsing model. Well, I bought this one too thinking the design was interesting, but...
なんかね、薄いんだよね。
Somehow, it's thin.
薄いね。
Thin.
なんか色が薄いんだよね。
The color is somehow light.
薄いですね。
It is light.
君みたいな人がかけない想定なんだよね。で、調べてみたらなんか、あのちょっとおしゃれめな女優さんとかがかけてて、そう言うことですよ。
It's probably designed assuming someone like you wouldn't wear it. When I looked into it, apparently stylish actresses and such wear them, so that's what it is.
これ俺じゃねえなと思って買ったはいいけどずっとつけてなかったんですよ。
I bought it thinking "this isn't me," but I never ended up wearing it.
君の新衣装だ。
It's your new outfit!
新衣装、新アイテム、なるほど。
A new outfit, a new item, I see.
ただねこれだけだと、やっぱり、あの、グラサンだけじゃあ、わかんないかなって、前回のトータルコーディネートが
But just with this, I thought sunglasses alone might not make it clear, considering the previous total coordination...
あ、見えてきましたよこの流れ。
Ah, I'm starting to see where this is going.
はい、じゃあ次じゃ
Right, then next...
I RIDE SO I DON'T CHOKE PEOPLE
「俺はバイクに乗ってるから人の首を締めずに済んでんだぜ」
"I ride a motorcycle so I don't have to choke people."
これを着るんだよお前が
You're gonna wear this!
これ新衣装なんですか!?
Is this my new outfit!?
マフィア梶田なりきりセットってこと？
A Mafia Kajita cosplay set?
一点思ったのがエピソードないよね？
One thing I thought: you don't have an episode for this, do you?
この2点にあなたのエピソード存在してませんよね？
Neither of these two items has any connection to you, do they?
白上さんにあげるためだけに用意してるんで
I prepared them solely to give to Shirakami-san.
まだ精度を上げる道具がひとつある
There's one more tool to increase the accuracy.
こちらのGlockです。Glock 17、プレゼントいたします。
This Glock. Glock 17, as a present.
おお、それは嬉しいです！
Oh, I'm happy about that!
お前チャカ持ち歩いてんの？
You carry a piece around with you?!
一応アイドルなんですけども
I'm an idol, you know...
まあここまでの流れはね、全部茶番ということでまあ
Well, up to this point, it's all just a skit.
お膳立てはしましたよ、お膳立てはしましたよ
We set the stage, we set the stage.
あるんですよ、モノホンがね。モノホンが、ほら。
There is a real one. The real deal, look.
出しますかもう？出しますかね？あれ。
Should we bring it out now? Should we?
そこに俺っちがいるから、ちょっと取って出して。
Orecchi's over there, so reach over and get it out.
こちら！はあー！はい！わあー！
Here! Wow! Yes! Waaah!
大川ぶくぶかけるわしゃがな 5周年おめでとう！
Bkub Ookawa x Washagana! Congrats on 5 years!
ありがとうございます！！いや、待ってください。
Thank you so much!! Wait, hold on.
サインも入っている。
There are signatures too.
ちょっとね、何かしようって言っても何がいいのか全く分からない。
When we tried to think of what to gift, we had no idea what would be good.
なんか普通に私物だと今のラインナップになっちゃうし
If it were just normal personal items, it'd fit the current lineup,
俺もなんかわけわかんない時計とかあげだす。
and I'd end up giving weird watches or something.
そのブルガリくれるんでしょ？なんでや！
You're gonna give me that Bulgari, right? Why would I!
今回コラボしたことも思い出に残りつつってなると何かっていうので、大川先生に相談して描いてもらったんですね。
So to make our collaboration memorable, we consulted Bkub Ookawa-sensei and had him draw this for us.
ちょっと一点問題がありまして、あの、大川さん描いてる最中気持ちよくなったんでしょうね。僕らのサインを書くスペースを考えてくれてなかった。
But there was one problem—Ookawa-san probably got too into drawing it and didn't leave any space for our signatures!
一切ない。だからちょっとこのあてずような書き方になって。
There's literally none. So we had to write them like this in the margins.
いや、中村さんマイク・タイソンみたいになってる。
Nakamura-san, you look like Mike Tyson.
でもまあ、これね、あの、この世に1枚だから、是非大事にしてもらえると
But hey, since there's only one of these in the world, we'd love for you to cherish it.
大事にさせていただきます！ありがとうございます！
I will cherish it! Thank you very much!
飾ってね、飾ります。もう神棚があるので、そこに一度、はい、捧げておこうと思います。
Display it, huh? I'll display it. I have a household shrine, so I'll dedicate it there once.
この4点セットで。4点セットで、わかりました。
With this set of four items. A set of four, got it.
わしゃがな、ある、私物。白上が？え、持ってきてんの？
Washagana has some personal items. Shirakami brought some? E, you brought them?
はい、ちょっとだけお話をさせていただきたいなというものが、出していただいてもいいですか。うわ、中村さんの方から
Yes, there's something I'd like to talk about just a little bit, could you bring it out? Wow, from Nakamura-san's side...
こちらですね、こちらはですね、ファイナルファンタジーXIVの、あの、オーケストラコンサートで、サイリュウムとして販売されました「エルピスの花」というお花でございます。
This here is the "Elpis Flower," sold as a glow stick at the Final Fantasy XIV Orchestra Concert.
ゲーム中に出てくる設定的に大事なアイテムなんだよね。そうなんです。
It's an important item lore-wise that appears in the game. That's right.
これをさ、その、みんなさん持ってくざさいって。パクりてぇよな！？パクりてぇ！
And I'm like, "Everyone, please take one." I wanna rip it off! I wanna rip it off!
この悍ましい。ねえ、これ、こっちの方がいいな？こっちいいな？
This grotesque... Hey, is this one better? Is that one better?
ホロライブ内にも、じつはあのやっているプレイヤーの子がいて、その子と一緒に実はコンサートに行かせていただきまして。
Within Hololive, there's actually a player of the game, and I actually went to the concert together with her.
で、もうめちゃめちゃハマってたゲームだったので、
It was a game I was super hooked on,
こうやってこういう形ででお花もともして、そういうプレイヤーに対してもすごい愛のあふれるコンサートだったなという事で、思い出の品として持ってきました。
so bringing this flower to light up like this—it was a concert full of love for the players, so I brought it as a memento.
これさ、あかりつくの？どうやって光るの？
Does this light up? How does it glow?
あの、下に、お花のしたのところにボタンがあると思うんですけども、そうですね、そこですね。それを、曲中の途中で、一斉につけてくださいていうシーンがあるんで、前から順番に一斉にお花が咲くっていう。なるほど。
Uh, there's a button under the flower, right? Ah, yes, right there. There's a scene during the song where everyone turns them on all at once, and the flowers bloom in order from the front. I see.
綺麗だね。そうなんです、ゲーム本編にもそういう演出がありまして。
That's pretty. Indeed, there's a similar presentation in the game itself.
ホロライブのメンバーと一緒に行けたっていうのがまた思い出深くて、普段までサラリー一緒に遊んでる
Being able to go with Hololive members makes it so nostalgic and memorable, since we always hang out together.
そっちの事務所の仲間いっぱいいていいよな！俺らも入れてくんね？
It's nice having lots of friends in your agency! Can you let us in too?
ホロスターズとしてファンサとかできますか？
As Holostars, can you do fan service and stuff?
ファンサ？普段からやっとるやっとる！
Fan service? We do it all the time!
ファンサって何？トマトぶつけるんだっけ？何処の国のファンサっすか！
What is fan service? Throwing tomatoes? What kind of country's fan service is that?!
最近指ハートとかも流行ってますし。あ、そうですね、リス。
Recently, finger hearts and stuff have been trending too. Ah, yes, Ris.
俺、これ見るたびに、マネー、マネー、マネーって思う。
Every time I see this, I think, "Money, money, money."
違います！！お札を数えて、お札を弾いてる指だと思い込んで。違います違います！アイドルがそんなこと！お札をこう弾いてるもんだと思って。
That's wrong!! You think it's counting bills, flicking bills! No way! An idol wouldn't! Thinking it's flicking bills like this!
この動画どこで出るかちゃんと理解してる？知っとるわ！
Do you understand where this video is going to be released? Of course I do!
200万人が観とるぞ。
2 million people are gonna watch it.
ちょっと待て、俺いって恐ろしいこと気づいたんだけどさ、あの、時間が、やばいね。
Wait a second, I just realized something terrifying... time is running out.
まだ、まだ企画あるんですよ。まだあるね。
There are still more segments. Still more, huh.
フブキちゃんからプレゼントがあるそうです！！
It seems Fubuki-chan has a present for us!!
なに！？プレゼント！？
What?! A present?!
はよ出して、早く！
Hurry up and bring it out!
はい、こちら。はい、こちらですね、白上がですね、80万人記念の時に出しましたTシャツでございます。
Yes, here. Yes, this is the T-shirt Shirakami released for her 800k subscriber milestone.
かっけえやん。はい、こちら。
That's pretty cool. Yes, this one.
スカーフをポチッポチッってできるんですけど
You can button and unbutton the scarf...
ちょっと私が今着てる衣装が違うんですけども
Though the outfit I'm wearing right now is different.
ほら、このね、キツネと王冠と…
Look, this fox, crown and...
ハイ、スカーフでちょっとキャラクターっぽくない感じで、普段でも着れるようなイメージして作っていただく機会がございまして。
Right, with a scarf, designed to not look too character-like, something you could wear in everyday life.
ありがとうございます！手に入れてくれた方、ありがとうございます！うわあ！
Thank you! To those who got one, thank you! Wow!
では続いて、行きますか。あと5…、3分くらいで…、3分！できるか！？
Now let's move on. About 5... 3 minutes... 3 minutes! Can we do it?!
ではこちら、こちらなんですけど、スタンドミニアクリルキーホルダー ホロライブはぐみーつ…
Now, this one here, is the Stand Mini Acrylic Keyholder Hololive Hug Meets...
あ、いるね。
Ah, they're here.
そうなんです！右上に今回1期生とあのホロライブミスというあの英語圏のメンバーのラインナップとなっております！
That's right! In the top right, we have the 1st gen and Hololive Myth English branch members lineup!
なるほど、中村祐志に箱の開封を任せるとして、
I see, leaving the box unboxing to Yuichi Nakamura...
の、側面をね、そうですね、絶妙にこう綺麗に開けない気が済まない男だから。
and opening the side neatly, because he's a guy who can't stand not opening it neatly.
じゃ、奥の方から引いていきましょうかね。
Well then, let's draw from the back.
じゃ、私行きますよ。
Well, I'll go.
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
お1人目が…あ、夜空メルちゃんです！
The first person is... Ah, Yozora Mel-chan!
夜空メルちゃんは私と同じホロライブ1期生のメンバーでして、魔界の天才ヴァンパイアなんです。
Yozora Mel-chan is a fellow Hololive 1st generation member, a genius vampire from the Demon Realm.
ヴァンパイアなのか？
A vampire?
そうなんです、ヴァンパイアなんです。へえ…、これなんか、キャラ被り…
That's right, she's a vampire. Eh... Is this... character overlap...
同族の方とかいるんですか？
Are there others of the same kind?
ああ、ヴァンパイアの方ですか？ヴァンパイアの人は他には…
Ah, vampires? Other vampires...
ホロライブ内にはいないんですけど、まあVtuber色々な方がいらっしゃいますので、もちろんヴァンパイアの方々も沢山おられますね。
There aren't any inside Hololive, but since there are all kinds of VTubers, of course there are many vampires.
思い出すだけで4、5人はいるかもしれない。
Just thinking about it, there might be 4 or 5.
やっぱ人気なんだね。
So they're popular after all.
じゃあ次の子行きますか？
Shall we go to the next one?
はい、次々。
Yes, next next.
あ、赤いハートちゃんだ！
Ah, Akai Haato-chan!
はい、ハートちゃんもですね、ホロライブ1期生の女の子なんですけど、
Yes, Haato-chan is also a Hololive 1st generation girl,
蜘蛛とかを食べた実績があります。
who has a track record of eating spiders and things.
蜘蛛食べた？
Eaten spiders?
はい、あのタランチュラとかを配信内で食べたことがある。
Yes, she has eaten tarantulas and such during streams.
頼まれて？
Was she asked to?
いやもう自ら進んで…
No, she went ahead of her own accord...
やるねえ！ハートちゃまクッキング…負けてたぁ！
That's something! Haatochama Cooking... We lost!
うち山まだやってないから蜘蛛喰うの。
Our Yamato hasn't eaten spiders yet.
そう。古いレーションしか食ってない。
That's right. Only eating old rations.
古いレーションと古いビッグマックしか食ってない。
Only eating old rations and old Big Macs.
一緒に食べたりは？
Have you ever eaten together?
ええ、でも本当にデビューしたての頃に、なんかね、虫は食べたことありました。
Well, back when we just debuted, um, I did eat insects.
マジで？
Seriously?
はい、ありましたね。
Yes, I did.
興味本位。
Out of curiosity.
やっぱりホロライブ入りません。
I guess I won't join Hololive after all.
登竜門が虫じゃないですから！大丈夫ですから！
The gateway isn't insects! It's totally fine!
新人はまずこれいけるってタランチュラ出される。
Newcomers are given tarantulas to test if they can handle it.
俺まだ頑張れるか、じゃ残って俺だけじゃあつって、俺まだここいけるかもしれない。
Can I still push through? If I stay and it's just me... I might still be able to go here.
いやいやそんなことないです。
No, no, that's not it.
じゃ次行こうか。
Well, let's go to the next one.
あ、ぐらちゃんだ！
Ah, Gura-chan!
がるぐらちゃんですね。ぐらちゃんはあの海外圏のミスのメンバーで、あのサメなんです。
Gawr Gura-chan. Gura-chan is a member of Myth from overseas, a shark.
サメちゃんなんです。このデビュー配信の時に画面に出てきて一言目が「あ」だったんですよね。
Shark-chan. During her debut stream, when she appeared on screen, her very first word was 'a'.
えの「あ」！もうそれで凄いあの海外の方ではバズりにバズりまして。
The 'a' of A! That blew up immensely among overseas viewers.
俺知ってるなこの子。
I know this kid.
あ、知ってますか？
Oh, you know her?
がるぐらちゃんだ。そうです、がるぐらちゃんです。サメで。
Gawr Gura-chan. That's right, Gawr Gura-chan. A shark.
そうなんですけど、日本語がすごくうまくて、日本語でたまに話してくれたりします。
That's right, but her Japanese is very good, and she sometimes talks in Japanese.
サメ食うの？
Do you eat shark?
食べないです。サメってコンテンツが人気だもんね、やっぱね。
No. Shark content is popular after all, right?
次はなんだ？意外と出ないですよ、フーチャン。出ないですね。
What's next? Surprisingly not appearing, Fu-chan. Not appearing.
あ、高梨キアラちゃんですね。
Ah, Takanashi Kiara-chan.
キアラちゃんもグラちゃんと同じグループで、『不死鳥』なんですよ。
Kiara-chan is in the same group as Gura-chan, she's a 'Phoenix'.
不死鳥？
A Phoenix?
はい、不死鳥なんです。
Yes, a phoenix.
はい、不死鳥も、火の鳥かい？
Yes, a phoenix... Is it a firebird?
そうなんです。チキンがすごく大好きといいますか。火の鳥なのにチキンが好き？
That's right. She loves chicken very much. A firebird that likes chicken?
あ、そうなんです。あのKFPということで、そう。
Ah, that's right. Called KFP, yes.
今度聞いといて、火の鳥では何編が好きか。
Next time ask her which arc of 'Phoenix' she likes best.
そこから取ってないと思うんでね。そこからじゃない？手塚先生じゃないと思うんで。
I don't think she took it from there. Isn't it from somewhere else? Probably not Tezuka-sensei.
あ、まつりさんですね。
Ah, Matsuri-san.
あ、まつりちゃーん！まつりちゃん？
Ah, Matsuri-chan! Matsuri-chan?
はい、夏色まつりちゃんです。この子も白上とと同じホロライブ1期生で、はい、チアリーダーをやっていますね。
Yes, Natsuiro Matsuri-chan. She is also a Hololive 1st gen member along with Shirakami, and yes, she does cheerleading.
えー、チアリーダー。もう歌とダンスが一番やっぱすごい可愛くて。
Eh, cheerleading. Her singing and dancing are just super cute.
はい、夏色ふぶきっていうコンビで配信とかでコラボをしたりとかしてます。
Yes, under the duo name Natsuiro Fubuki, they sometimes collaborate on streams and things.
いいね、応援して欲しいね。
That's nice, I want her to cheer me on.
チアリーディングして欲しい。
I want her to cheerlead for me.
感想が若干おっさんじみてね。
Your reaction sounds a bit like an old man's.
おっさんなんだからしょうがないでしょ！
I'm an old man, so it can't be helped!
いや確かにそうなんだけど、俺もさすがに思いつかなかったから。いや応援して欲しいね。
Well, that's true, but even I didn't think of that. Yeah, I want her to cheer me on.
多分だけどもコメント欄そう言うのあふれてると思うよ。「応援して欲しい」っていう。
Probably the comment section is full of things like that. 'I want her to cheer me on'.
俺も俺も私も私も。
Me too, me too, me too.
だっみんな疲れてんだもんおっさん。おっさんみんな疲れてるのよ。
Because everyone is tired, us old guys. Old guys are all tired.
はい、続きましてアメリアさんから。
Yes, next is Amelia-san.
あ、ワトソン・アメリアちゃーん！アメリアちゃんですね、探偵ですね。
Ah, Watson Amelia-chan! Amelia-chan, a detective.
職業シリーズはあるんだね。
So there's a occupation series.
そうです、探偵はありますね、職業シリーズも。
Yes, there's a detective one, occupation series.
探偵っていうぐらいだから相当頭いいんかい？
Since she's a detective, is she quite smart?
相当頭いいんかい？
Is she really that smart?
どうなんですかね…
Well, I wonder...
そこは疑問なんかい
You're questioning that?
ちょっとPONなところがあったりしますけど
She can be a bit clumsy sometimes, but...
ちょっとPONなところがある
She does have clumsy moments.
探偵味を感じる部分はあるの？
Does she feel like a detective at all?
ありますね…
Oh, definitely...
なさそうだよ？
Doesn't look like it?
あ、当たり、当たりが出ちゃった。
Ah, it popped up.
あ、出た！やった、ありがとうございます。
Ah, it's out! Thank you very much.
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki!
はい。
Yeah.
この子はどんな子なんだい？
What kind of girl is she?
この子はですね、そうですね。
Well, this girl is...
わしゃがなを毎週見逃さずに、あの、アラートをしっかりとかけておりまして、はい。
She sets alerts to never miss Okayu's "Ojikan IV" every week,
ツイートを見かけたらRTして見ようねと、
and always retweets whenever she sees a tweet,
布教をしているキツネですね。
a fox spreading the word.
なんて素晴らしい子なんだ！
What a wonderful girl!
俺これから推すよ！
I'm going to start stanning her!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ぜひともよろしくお願いします。
Please treat her well.
初めて知ったけどこれからも推すわ。
Just found out about her, but I'll start stanning her now!
フブキちゃんっていうのかぁ！
Her name is Fubuki-chan!
チェックしていくよ！
I'll check her out!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal!
アキ・ローゼンタールちゃんですね。
Aki Rosenthal-chan, yes.
ローゼンタール
Rosenthal...
ハーフエルフなんですよ、この子は。
She's a half-elf, you know?
ハーフエルフなんです。
She's a half-elf!
ベリーダンスがすごい得意なんです。
She's really good at belly dancing.
ベリーダンス？
Belly dancing?
ベリーダンスだね。
Belly dancer, huh?
そうなんです。なので楽曲もけっこうその、アラビアン的な、
That's right. So her music is...
その民族チックの中でちょっと妖艶に踊っていくという。
with a bit of ethnic flair, dancing enchantingly.
面白っ。
Interesting.
ハーフエルフのベリーダンス。
A half-elf belly dancer!
見たことねえ俺。
I've never seen a half-elf belly dancer.
俺もねえし、みんなねえよ。
I haven't either. None of us have.
基本的にはねえよ。
Basically, never.
一伊那栖ちゃんですかね？
Ninomae Ina'nis-chan, right?
二のまえ いなにすちゃんです。
Ninomae Ina'nis-chan.
いわゆるこう、邪神って言っていいのでしょうかね？
You could say she's... occult?
邪神？知ってますか。
She's an occult?
そうなんです、タコなんです。
That's right, she's an octopus!
冒涜的な…
Heretical?
そう、ちょっと冒涜的なんですけども、
Yeah, a bit heretical, but...
声が本当に可愛くて、透き通ってて、あと
her voice is just so cute, it melts your heart,
絵がすごく上手いんですよ。
and her art is so good!
イラストがめちゃめちゃ上手で…
Her illustrations are super good!
じゃあ、これラストです。
Okay, this is the last one.
森カリオペちゃん！森カリオペちゃんですね。
Mori Calliope-chan! Mori Calliope-chan!
この子はラップがとにかくすごいんです。
This girl's rap is just amazing!
ラッパー？ラッパーなんですよ。
A rapper?
いろんな有名の方とコラボしたりとか、LIVEとかもしてまして、
She collaborates with various famous people and holds live streams,
ぜひラッパーの方は聴いて頂きたい。
so I definitely want rap fans to listen to her.
Lotus Juiceに勧めておくわ。
I'll recommend her to Lotus Juice.
あ、ぜひぜひぜひ！
Please do, please do!
お願いします。
I'd appreciate it.
お互い知ってるかもしれないじゃん。
They might already know each other.
もうバトル済みかもしれない。
They might have even battled before.
まさか、バトルしてんだ。
No way, they've battled?
バトルしてた。
They've battled!
この子は人間なのかい？
Is this one human?
この子は死神なんです。
This girl is a Grim Reaper!
死神？
A Grim Reaper?
なんでデビューの最初に作った曲が「失礼しますが、RIP❤」っていう。
Yeah, her debut song was called "Excuse My Rudeness, But Dead".
そう、「失礼しますが、死んでください」っていう。
Like, "Excuse my rudeness, please die".
失礼しますがレストインピースね。なるほどね。
"Excuse My Rudeness, But Rest In Peace", huh?
そうなんです。よければ聴いてみてくだサーイ！
That's right, so please give it a listen if you'd like.
めちゃくちゃイカした楽曲じゃねえかよ。
That's not a badass song title at all!
そうなんです。もう本当にかっこいいラップなので。
That's right, it's a really cool rap song.
君は同僚の紹介がうまいな。
You're really good at introducing your peers.
あ、いやいや、プレゼン能力が…
Oh no, not at all, your presentation skills...
深み深い。
are so profound.
ありがとうございます。もうホロライブのメンバー大好きなのですね、
Thank you very much. I just love Hololive members so much,
こうやって紹介できて嬉しいです！
so I'm so happy I could introduce them!
いや、これ全部すか？
So is that all of them?
これで全部ですね。
Is that all of them?
これではい、出てるものは、全員紹介させていただきました。
We've introduced all the ones shown here.
はい、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ここであれですね、そのフブキさんからお知らせ。
Now, here's an announcement from Fubuki-chan!
お知らせ？
An announcement?
ちょっとお知らせがあります。
I do have an announcement!
なんとですね、今回白上フブキ5周年ということで
To celebrate Shirakami Fubuki's 5th anniversary,
グッズが出まーす！
merchandise is coming out!
そのグッズ、こちら！
Let's take a look at the goods.
こちらです！
Here it is!
こちらですね、
This is...
B2のタペストリーで、ひらゆお先生描き下ろし野…
a B2 tapestry featuring newly drawn art by Yosai Kihara,
ちょっと温泉に入っている、タペストリーでございまーす。
with recorded audio included.
このね、わしゃがなの一コマ前が実のホロライブゲーマーズというメンバーで、
One of my previous songs was actually with Hololive Gamers,
あの、温泉に行ったという、はい、ことでちょっとそれをイメージして作っていただきましたー！
so we created this with that image in mind.
そしてもう一つ、こちら！
And another item is this!
こちらせんちゃ先生描き下ろしの、アクリルジオラマスタンドですー。
This is the acrylic diorama stand with newly drawn art by Sencha-sensei.
こちらはね、ちょっと宿でみんなでゆっくりしているというイメージで。
This one pictures us all relaxing at an inn.
めちゃめちゃ酒飲んでるじゃん。
You guys are drinking a lot, huh?
そうなんです。
That's right!
めちゃめちゃビール飲んでる。
Drinking a ton of beer!
ビールをちょっと、はい、みんなで乾杯しようかと、思って、こちらでーす。
We figured we'd all cheers with beer, so we went with this.
そして続いて、こちら！
And next is this!
こちらはアイマスクでーす！
This is an eye mask!
こちら白上のあの、オリジナルキャラクター、オリジナルマスコットで、見ているっていうちょっとキャラクターがいるんですけども、その見ているのアイマスクでございまーす。
It's designed after Shirakami's original mascot character.
ちょっとこちら実物が、お手に、あると思うんですけど…
Wait, I'm actually going to try putting it on right now.
(笑)
(Laughs)
お前を見ているぞ！
I've got my eyes on you!
そうですね、まさにそんなキャラで、その、ものかげか…
That's right, it's literally that character!
うわ、中村悠一さんがつけてるー！
Wait, Nakamura-san is wearing it too!
俺たちがお前を見ている、見ているぞと。
We've got our eyes on you!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
俺いいなー。
I like that.
ちょっとそれをね、あのファンのみんなにもつけていただいて、ライブとか色々…
I want all the fans to wear these during lives and stuff.
おでんにつけても、ネコ耳みたいね。
Even if you wear it on your forehead, it looks like cat ears.
あ、確かに、そうですね。
Ah, true, that's right.
ネコ耳みたい。はい、はい。
Like cat ears, yes, yes.
かわいい！
Cute!
いいやんこれ。
This is nice.
もう一つ、こちらでーす。
And one last item, this!
こちら、レザーモーテルキーホルダーですね。まぁ今回、温泉とか宿とか出てるので、まぁレザーのモーテルキーホルダーで、みんなにつけてほしいなという。
This is a leather motel keychain, and since hot springs and inns are featured in our goods, we'd love for everyone to use this leather motel keychain.
フブキハウスに入っちゃっていいのかい？
Can we check into Fubuki House?
そうです、フブキハウスにちょっとご招待用の、っていう、その1005ってのは…
Yes, please come visit Fubuki House. As for the "1005"...
は、10月5日が実は私の誕生日でして。
October 5th is actually my birthday!
はーい！
Yeah!
そう、ホロブック
Yeah, Holobook...
お届けいただきましたー！
It was delivered to me!
はい、こちらですね、活動5周年記念フルセット購入特典がございまして、
Yes, for this, there's a purchase bonus for the 5th anniversary full set,
数量限定で白上フブキ直筆サイン＆箱推し複製メッセージ入りのポストカードがありまして、
a limited-edition postcard featuring Fubuki Shirakami's autograph and a replicated message,
通常版は複製サイン＆メッセージ入りとなっております。
and the standard version features a replicated autograph and message.
なるほど、参考にします。
I see, I'll take notes.
ねえ。これいろいろ使いそうな感じですね。
Yeah. This feels like it'd be useful in various ways.
本当ですか？結構あの直筆サインも本当にあのたくさんの方々が買ってくださるので、仕事の合間とかに直筆でキュキュキュと...
Really? Since a lot of people buy the autographed version, I sign them quickly in between work...
うちはね、ノウハウを吸収するタイプの番組だからね。
Well, our show's the type to absorb know-how, you see.
本当ですか？え、でも...
Really? Uh, but...
わかりやすく言うと「パクる」っていう...
To put it simply, "stealing"...
え、でもあわよくば参考にしてやって頂けたら白上も応募しますけどもね！
Hey, but if you could use it as reference, I'd apply for it too!
はい、もちろんです！ぜひぜひなんかグッズの参考になるのは嬉しいです。
Yes, of course! I'd be so glad if it helps as reference for goods.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
さあ、ありがとうございました。さまざまなね、告知もいただいて...
Well, thank you very much. We've received various announcements...
いやー、やっぱり力のあるところは出すものは違いますね。
Man, companies with real clout really put out different kinds of stuff.
違うな。
For real.
これとかさ、よくできてんなあ、おい。
This and stuff, it's really well-made, man.
ありがとうございます！材質も良いしデザインもよく印刷出てて...わあ、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! The material is nice and the design is printed so well... Wow, thank you!
めちゃんこかわいい。
It's super cute.
なんか、なんだ？何族だこれ？何族？
What is this? What tribe is this? What tribe?
ほらあの、目の周りのアイマスク出しましょうよ。
Hey, let's bring out the eye mask for around the eyes.
実写のですか？
The live-action one?
うん、中村さんがで、中村さんのドロンとした目の周りの感じ...ドロンとした...
Yeah, Nakamura's... that droopy look around Nakamura's eyes... droopy...
ぶくちゃんに描いて貰えばいいじゃん！そう、でもいいね。
You should have Bkub-chan draw it! Yeah, but that's good.
ぜひぜひ出してください！
Please definitely release it!
ということでね、えー、たっぷりと、50分近く収録してきましたけども、大幅に切ります。20分くらいカットされますけれども、もったいない！
So yeah, uh, we recorded for nearly 50 minutes, but we're cutting a lot. About 20 minutes will be cut, what a waste!
さあ、どうだった、ぶくちゃん？
Now, how was it, Bkub-chan?
いやー、楽しいですね！やっぱりちょっとまあ、時間もあっという間で、もっとお話したかったんですけども、本当に今回なんか、呼ばせて頂きまして、ありがとうございます！
Man, it's so fun! Time flew by so fast, and I wanted to talk more, but thank you so much for inviting me this time!
楽しかったなら、うちの子になっちゃうかい？
If it was fun, why don't you become one of our kids?
専属VTuberに！一緒に。
As an exclusive VTuber! Together.
あー、ちょっと、いい、それもちょっといいかもしれないけど、取り分は均等に割るけどね。
Ah, wait, that might be nice too, though our shares would be split evenly.
大人の話はあとで、ほらさん。インターンっていう形とか...
We'll talk about adult matters later, Hora-san. Like an internship format...
まぁちょっと、あとで契約の面を...しっかりと言い訳します。
Well, we'll talk about contract terms later... We'll make proper excuses.
やめろよお前じゃあその、愛情表現やめないで。それきゅんです、きゅんです、きゅんなんです！¥マネーにきゅんです！最悪やもう。
Stop it, man, don't stop that expression of affection. That's "kyun, kyun, kyun!" It's "kyun" for yen money! This is the worst.
俺らの評価だけ最近どうなってんだ？
What's been happening to our reputation lately?
皆さんね、あの、盛り上げてるだけですからね！
Everyone, you know, we're just hyping things up!
そうそうそう！本当じゃないからね！うぶちゃんと仲良くやってますんでね、面白と思って言ってるだけだからね。
Yeah, yeah, yeah! It's not real! We get along fine with Ubu-chan, so we're just saying it for laughs.
皆さんの方...よろしくお願いします！いや、ありがとね。
Everyone... please treat us well! Yeah, thanks.
じゃあ、ぶくちゃんありがとうございました。えー、いつもの締め...
Well, Bkub-chan, thank you very much. Uh, the usual closing...
はい、分かりました！ではみなさんご視聴いただきありがとうございます！白上フブキチャンネルと、Washagana TVの登録、白上フブキのTwitterとWashagana TVのTwitterのフォロー、よろしくお願いします！高評価、メンバーシップもよろしくね！
Yes, understood! Well then everyone, thank you for watching! Please subscribe to the Fubuki Shirakami Channel and Washagana TV, and follow Fubuki Shirakami's Twitter and Washagana TV's Twitter! Please also give us a like and check out our memberships!
ワシャガナTV
Washagana TV